Mss.Rec.88 Mss.Rec.88
American Philosophical Society
Tuscarora language materials narrated by Chief Elton Greene
1971-1972
Mss.Rec.88
American Philosophical Society
6.0 Reel(s)
Tuscarora linguistic material, given by consultant in English and Tuscarora. Includes verbs, grammar, numerals, days, months, seasons, greetings, weather, body parts, and colors. Also includes a short speech given in Tuscarora, then English, on how Tuscarora chiefs are chosen and the preservation of Tuscarora language and customs. Recorded in 1971 and 1972, most likely in North Carolina.
6 sound tape reels (2 hr., 25 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 5 in.
Greene, Elton
Mithun, Marianne
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Marianne Mithun in 1972 (Acc. 1972 1546rec). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Sound recordings; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language
- Audio recordings
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 1, 1971-06-24; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:01; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Time--Terminology; Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 2, 1971-06-25; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:02; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 3, 1971-07-02; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:19; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Tuscarora language; Weather
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 4, 1971-07-07; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:01; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 5, 1971-07-13; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:32; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Colors, Words for; Human body--Terminology; Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 6, 1971-07-15; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:27; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 7 (The Lord's Prayer), 1971-07-19; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:46; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Lord's Prayer; Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 8, 1971-07-23; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:58; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 9, 1971-07-25; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:59; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
    Scope and Contents note
    Covers miscellaneous expressions and grammatical constructions, followed by a short speech given in Tuscarora, then English, on how Tuscarora chiefs are chosen and the preservation of Tuscarora language and customs.
    Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 10, 1971-07-28; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:36; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne
  - Tuscarora Language Materials, Side 11, 1971-08-03; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:10; Greene, Elton; Mithun, Marianne